Charlie Van Norman

charlievannorman.com (650) 440-5445

I specialize in VR/AR apps for medical, including training, therapy, pain management, and disease simulators. I am flexible, metrics driven, and lean towards biz dev/sales.

Highlights from my previous company (2013 - 2017) in four categories:

PROJECT MANAGER

- Formed product vision and team
- Successfully developed and launched 2 math games that resulted in 25,000 users
- Organized 25+ user test events
- Co-managed a Kickstarter campaign raising \$48,000
- Hired and managed 8 employees and interns

CREATIVE DIRECTOR

- Lead game designer
- Math as foundational game mechanics
- Emergent, Turing-complete game behavior
- In-game level editor
- Produced 3 product showcase videos

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT

- Closed 4 distribution partners
- Partnered with gurus Dan Meyer, Jo Boaler who helped validate and popularize our brand
- Partnered with local math department leads at progressive middle schools
- Built initial community and customer base with 50+ Bay Area schools
- Participated in 10+ math education conferences

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Unity3D front-end game mechanics and behaviors across 200+ unique game objects
- C# back-end game architecture layer
- Full web stack on AWS, ubuntu, Apache, Django, Python, MySQL, HTML, jquery, js, css
- Javascript API for compiled WebGL <--> Django/SQL functions
- Built a runtime editor layer for live content creation and sharing
- Wrote command line tools for one-button deployment and testing

EXPERIENCE

2017 Extended Reality Consultant

I help startups to find b2b market opportunities for VR and AR, and to discover, spec, design, and build applications in the space.

2016 - 2017 Co-founder, Super Math World - Imaginary Number Co

- Developed a tool for creating, editing and sharing levels
- Designed and built the game mechanics and game architecture
- Built the full web stack on javascript, python/django/AWS
- Formed key partnerships with distributors and math celebrities

2015 Contractor, Mouse Brain Explorer - 3Scan VR mouse brain navigation game for Exploratorium

2013 - 2016 Tech program director - Synapse Middle School

- Directed the afterschool technical program for three quarters
- Designed curriculum for and managed a math summer camp

2013 - 2016 Co-founder, Mathbreakers - Imaginary Number Co

- Co-founded the company and recruited a team
- Prototyped and tested early games to find product market fit
- Traveled to local schools to establish our first customer base

2012 Entrepreneur, Start Up Chile

Built a startup resources hub for finding investors, local events, incubators, competitiors, customers, and employees

2011 Contractor, Code Hero - Primer Labs

Lead developer and designer of Code Hero, an FPS game that teaches javascript by modifying the game itself during gameplay using eval()

2010 Founder - Fractal Games

- Hired and managed art team
- Partnered with programmers for game logic
- Produced two iOS titles, Santa's Last Stand and Bank Defense

2009 Property Manager - Alexander Forrest

I rehabilitated two failing complexes with 60 and 110 units, including lease up, rent collections, repairs, materials budgeting, and hiring and managing staff, leading to the profitability of both properties and the sale of one property.

EDUCATION

2010 - 2012 San Francisco State

M.B.A. Entrepreneurship program (dropped out to found a company)

2010 Urban Land Institue

Real Estate Development Program

2001 - 2007 Cal Poly Pomona

B.S. International Business

2 years Mechanical Engineering + Physics classes

2006 Salamanca, Spain

Immersive Spanish program and business classes

2002 - 2003 Beijing, China

International student program Taught English on the side